Zhang Ruipu?
♪ Through the mist, we walk side by side
across endless mountains and seas ♪
♪ Each sunrise brings hope,
and every sunset answers in kind ♪
♪ Drawn by the heart's call ♪
♪ We brave wind and frost,
free beneath the boundless sky ♪
♪ Every moonrise glows with pure radiance,
and every moonset fades into a dream ♪
♪ In the years to come, I'll ponder it ♪
♪ Across the vast mortal world,
our spirits soaring high ♪
♪ We vowed to forge ahead together ♪
♪ After weathering life's storms ♪
♪ I look back on our days
of youth and freedom ♪
♪ Now rusted by time,
swallowed by a boundless crimson tide ♪
♪ All love and hatred in this world
mean nothing anymore ♪
♪ A life of highs and lows ♪
♪ Yet never shared with you ♪
♪ Downing wine
and jeering at the absurd fate ♪
♪ I'm left alone,
wandering in the moonlight ♪
♪ Holding the blade
that shimmers in bleakness ♪
♪ Across the vast mortal world,
our spirits soaring high ♪
♪ We vowed to forge ahead together ♪
♪ After weathering life's storms ♪
♪ I look back on our days
of youth and freedom ♪
♪ Now rusted by time,
swallowed by a boundless crimson tide ♪
♪ All love and hatred in this world
mean nothing anymore ♪
♪ A life of highs and lows ♪
♪ Yet never shared with you ♪
♪ Now rusted by time,
swallowed by a boundless crimson tide ♪
♪ All love and hatred in this world
mean nothing anymore ♪
♪ A life of highs and lows ♪
♪ Yet never shared with you ♪
♪ Downing wine
and jeering at the absurd fate ♪
♪ I'm left alone,
wandering in the moonlight ♪
♪ Holding the blade
that shimmers in bleakness ♪
♪ Now rusted by time,
swallowed by a boundless crimson tide ♪
♪ All love and hatred in this world
mean nothing anymore ♪
♪ A life of highs and lows ♪
♪ Yet never shared with you ♪
They are taking turns
to attack you and wear you out!
Over there! There he is!
Shrimpie,
why are you here?
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 10]
Zhang Hailou,
you didn't disappoint me.
It's all over now.
What on earth happened here?
Who wants to kill you?
These men are clearly more
than just robbers.
Our deal
doesn't oblige me to explain it to you.
Keep doing what you're supposed to do.
Who's this lady?
She's more terrifying than a monster.
Does someone like her
really need our protection?
It only means
that her enemies are more formidable
than we think.
Tally up our losses.
Next, we must take control.
Otherwise, the deal is pointless.
Do it.
Come on.
[The Nan'an]
[A few days later]
Those assassins have all been locked up.
As for your friend's corpse,
Miss Dong said she would take care of it.
So don't worry.
They thought you were Steven,
so they gave you the best medicine.
I didn't expect you to be so fit
and recover so quickly.
You should at least eat something.
Actually, I still don't get it.
I mean, I am a stowaway.
And we caused such a huge mess together.
Why did she let us stay
in such a nice suite
instead of killing us?
Plague,
actually...
Actually, I can understand how you feel.
Before getting on the ship,
my boss committed suicide
right in front of me
because of the alcohol prohibition.
I will never forget that scene
for the rest of my life.
I had no other choice.
With nowhere else to go,
I had to head for Jinfan
to find my brother.
What else could we do?
There are many things you can't hide from,
no matter how much you want to.
But those left behind must keep living.
We have to live well.
And it's not just for ourselves.
Don't you
have anyone you care about?
Mentor,
what are you drawing?
Your true nature is a snake.
A snake
will devour everything.
You must overcome your true nature.
Do you still remember what I told you?
I remember.
Can you do it?
I can.
There's a big difference
between hearing it and doing it.
When you finally manage to do it,
that's when you pay the price.
Only then will you know what I mean.
But you are lucky,
having Zhang Haixia by your side—
he will remind you.
Did you hear that?
Be nice to me.
Put this on when I'm not around
in the future.
Look at it before every action.
Plague.
Plague?
I'll just take a break.
You go ahead and count.
We have to count them all today anyway.
Bro, who are you?
You can't come in here.
Where are the robbers
who were on the ship earlier?
Hey, who are you?
They're mostly all dead.
Only a few of them are alive,
and they've been
locked up by Miss Dong.
After the ship docks,
t-they will be handed over to the police.
Where are they locked up?
Why are you so late?
And what the hell happened
to the bodies in those boxes?
It takes like forever.
I don't know where these bodies came from.
They've all been specially embalmed.
God knows what these Easterners
planned to do with them.
Well, see you later.
You don't need to ask me
any more questions.
I don't know anything,
and I won't say anything.
How did Zhang Haixia die?
Zhang Haixia!
How did he die?
Wait.
Which one
exactly are you asking about?
Zhang Haixia,
who is in his twenties
and paralyzed in both legs.
I know him.
He was very smart
and very formidable.
I hunted him down twice
before I finally killed him.
Tell me more details.
The first time was
when we killed Zhang Ruipu.
Back then, you
had a little girl with you, right?
While you were negotiating
with Zhang Ruipu,
my people
swapped her out.
That friend of yours
is pretty smart.
I still can't figure out
how he learned
that Zhang Ruipu and we were
not on the same side.
You have no idea
how much effort I put into the plan
to assassinate Zhang Ruipu...
Yet it was almost
ruined by a cripple.
His name is Zhang Haixia.
Keep that in mind.
Speak!
Fortunately,
Zhang Ruipu
was defeated by his own arrogance.
He underestimated his enemy.
Then,
I started hunting him down.
I found he boarded the Nan'an.
The poison was
taking a heavy toll on him back then.
We all thought
he was done for.
But we never thought
that he injured our men
and escaped to the third-class cabin.
Your friend is
really something.
Even with broken legs,
he still cornered me
this far.
His death is
such a pity.
Is the one disguised
as Zhang Haijiao dead?
You guys once
met in the third-class cabin.
If you haven't found her corpse,
it proves that
she has escaped.
Do you remember
that assassin named Bai Zhu?
A musketeer wanted
to torture her to death.
Sir, you're mistaken.
Do you know you're going to die?
One last question.
Who sent you?
Why did you kill the people
from the Archives?
Was it a warlord?
I don't know.
I was ordered
to spread the Twilight Grass,
bring all the people
from the Southern Archives
to the Nan'an,
and kill them all.
I really
don't know anything else.
[The Nan'an]
You...
Where have you been?
Why are you in such a mess again?
Are you okay?
Miss Dong repeatedly warned us
not to leave this room.
Eat as much as you can.
I've known him my whole life.
He used to complain
that I always acted recklessly
without considering consequences,
saying that I would die
sooner or later.
I never expected him
to die first.
Fine.
Oh, shit!
This is not over yet.
Those who excavated the shipwreck
to look for the Twilight Grass back then
were the warlord forces.
The Evil God is also
related to the warlords.
The Twilight Grass and the Evil God
[Mysterious Poison Is
Proliferating Rapidly]
are wreaking havoc in Nanyang again now.
[Causing Multiple Deaths in Xucheng]
And right here on the Nan'an,
[N P]
someone's been hunting down
the Archives agents
investigating the Twilight Grass.
As for what the warlords
in the Panhua Reef Case
want to do with the Twilight Grass,
there is no conclusion yet.
Panhua Reef?
I... I think I've heard of it.
Is it that haunted place?
Eat more.
Here, eat more if you can.
Have this, too.
Shrimpie,
you wouldn't die for nothing.
I will find out the forces behind this
and avenge you.
Attention, please.
This voyage is about to reach
the final destination, Xiacheng.
[The Nan'an]
Attention, please.
This voyage is about to reach
the final destination, Xiacheng.
After over a decade,
Zhang Hailou finally came home.
[Xiacheng]
This is also
where everything
[Xiacheng Pier]
about the Southern Archives
began.
I'll hand this over to the ship police
after getting off the ship.
Plague,
we're in Xiacheng.
Let's get off.
Plague...
Plague?
Why are you still here?
It's safe.
Relax.
I hear there are
some beautiful girls in Xiacheng.
He doesn't know, huh?
I guess so.
Miss Dong.
The ship is about to dock.
You were unwilling to see me before.
May I ask you a few questions?
Miss Dong?
Miss Dong,
the captured robbers have
been attacked.
Should we lock down the ship
and find out who it was?
No.
Stick to the original plan.
Whether alive or dead,
hand them over to the ship police.
Got it.
Times are hard.
Let's part ways here.
If your obsession persists
and you are still perplexed,
you may come here for a chat.
But remember,
it's best we don't meet.
There's nothing to say anyway.
We're home,
Haixia.
[Welcome]
Shrimpie,
we are back in Xiacheng.
[Xiacheng Pier]
We've finally arrived.
Yeah, I'm exhausted.